<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<resources>
    <!-- Nav bar -->
    <string name="app_name">Simple Ciphers</string>
    <string name="title_section1">About</string>
    <string name="title_section2">Caesar Shift</string>
    <string name="title_section3">Vigenère</string>
    <string name="title_section4">Autokey</string>
    <string name="title_section5">Keyword</string>
    <string name="title_section6">Affine</string>
    <string name="navigation_drawer_open">Open navigation drawer</string>
    <string name="navigation_drawer_close">Close navigation drawer</string>
    <string name="action_example">about this cipher</string>
    <string name="action_settings">Settings</string>
    
    <!-- About -->
    <string name="app_title">Simple \n\t\tCiphers</string>
    <string name="author">By MacKenzie O\'Bleness</string>

    <!-- Buttons -->
    <string name="character_button_off">All \nSymbols</string>
    <string name="character_button_on">Alphabet \nOnly</string>
    <string name="case_button_off">Match \nCase</string>
    <string name="case_button_on">Remove \nCase</string>
    <string name="mode_encrypt">Encrypt \nMode</string>
    <string name="mode_decrypt">Decrypt \nMode</string>
    
    <!-- Text Hints -->
    <string name="plaintext_enter_hint">\tenter plaintext here</string>
    <string name="ciphertext_display_hint">\tciphertext will be displayed here</string>
    <string name="ciphertext_enter_hint">\tenter ciphertext here</string>
    <string name="plaintext_display_hint">\tplaintext will be displayed here</string>
    <string name="key_hint">keyword</string>
    <string name="shift_num_hint">shift #</string>
    <string name="affine_multi_hint">select a multiplier</string>
    
    <!-- Errors & Notifications -->
    <string name="key_fixed_notification">nonalphabetic characters removed from keyword</string>
    <string name="empty_key_error">please enter a key</string>
    <string name="bad_int_error">please enter a whole number</string>
    <string name="no_message_error">please enter a message</string>
    
    <!-- About Cipher Popup -->
    <string name="about_title_base">About The </string>
    <string name="about_caesar">Caesar\'s Cipher (also known as a shift cipher) is a simple substitution cipher.
        To encrypt, each letter is replaced by the letter n positions to the right. For a shift of 2, a becomes c,
        b becomes d, and so on. To decrypt, each letter is moved n positions to the left. \n\nMore info: wikipedia.org/wiki/Caesar_cipher
    </string>
    <string name="about_vigenere">The Vigenère Cipher is simple polyalphabetic substitution cipher based on a keyword.
        The cipher is basically a series of Caesar shifts, where each letter of the keyword corresponds to the shift amount
        : a is a shift of 0, b is a shift of 1, and so on. The keyword is repeated, so for a three letter key \'abc\', every
        three letters starting with the first is shifted by \'a\', every three letters starting with the second is shifted by
        \'b\', and every three letters starting with the third is shifted by \'c\'. \n\nMore info: wikipedia.org/wiki/Vigenère_cipher
    </string>
    <string name="about_autokey">The Autokey Cipher is a polyalphabetic substitution cipher. (Note: this implementation is a 
        text-autokey cipher, as opposed to a key-autokey cipher.) The cipher is essentially a Vigenère Cipher, but instead 
        of repeating the keyword over the entire message, (which leads to vulnerabilities if an attacker can guess the key length)
        the plaintext is appended to the keyword. The message is then encoded like a normal Vigenère Cipher. When decoding the 
        ciphertext, each character is decoded normally, and then appended to the key for use later on. \n\nMore info: wikipedia.org/wiki/Autokey_cipher
    </string>
    <string name="about_keyword">The Keyword Cipher is a simple monoalphabetic substitution cipher. It creates a
        cipher alphabet based on a keyword. The keyword is the start of the cipher alphabet, with all letters unused by the keyword
        following in their typical order. For example, the cipher alphabet created by the keyword \'now\' would be NOWABCDEFGHIJKLMPQRSTUVXYZ,
        where a would be mapped to n, b would be mapped to o, and so on. \n\nMore info: wikipedia.org/wiki/Keyword_cipher
        </string>
    <string name="about_affine">The Affine Cipher is a monoalphabetic substitution cipher. It maps letters to other letters following
        the formula (ax+b)mod(26), where a is represented as 0, b as 1, and so on. To decode, the equation c(x-b)mod(26), where c is the
        modular multiplicative inverse of a mod(26). In order to find this inverse, a and 26 (the size of the alphabet, for english, 26)
        must be coprime. As a result the options for a in the english alphabet are 1, 3, 5, 7, 9, 11, 15, 17, 19, 21, 23, and 25.\n
        It is worth noting that an encryption where a=1 is equivalent to a Caesar Shift of b, and an encryption where a=b=(26-1) is also
        known as the Atbash Cipher. \n\nMore info: wikipedia.org/wiki/Affine_cipher
    </string>

    <!-- Dropdown Options -->
    <string-array name="multiplier_array">
        <item>1</item>
        <item>3</item>
        <item>5</item>
        <item>7</item>
        <item>9</item>
        <item>11</item>
        <item>15</item>
        <item>17</item>
        <item>19</item>
        <item>21</item>
        <item>23</item>
        <item>25</item>
    </string-array>

</resources>
